Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/stephen-manasseh-4a24b0b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Sales, Business Development and Consulting.

Business Development Telecommunications

Stephen Manasseh

Sales Director SE Asia at Viavi Solutions Kuala Lumpur

Summary

Stephen has developed strong sales, business development, financial and technical skills in the telecoms industry with over 20 years of experience. He has wide experience in sales, business development, consulting and marketing across the South East Asia and Asia-Pacific region. A well-rounded background developed whilst working with MNCs such as Cisco, Tellabs, Nortel, Actel Consulting and Marconi in various technology fields.

At Cisco, Stephen was responsible for business development activities across Indonesia, Singapore, Malaysia and India. Stephen led the business development initiatives for Tellabs across Asia Pacific. At Nortel, Stephen provided technical and marketing support for the region. His ability of understanding next generation telecom architectures and providing corresponding business and financial justifications has resulted in new approaches in market penetration.

Stephen obtained his Electrical & Electronics Engineering degree from University of SouthBank, London graduating with BEng (Hons) First Class Honours (1993). He also obtained an MBA (Financial) with Merit from University of Nottingham (2007).

Specialties: Sales Director - South East Asia (ASEAN). Sales & Marketing, Business Development and Consulting in Telecoms Segment for South East Asia (ASEAN region).

Experience

Viavi Solutions Sales Director SE Asia January 2015 - Present (7 years) Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

Location Intelligence (Geolocation) & RAN Solutions

Actel Consulting
Principal Consultant SE Asia
June 2009 - October 2014 (5 years 5 months)
Malaysia

Principal Consultant / Regional Sales Director role across SE Asia.

Tellabs

Senior Business Development Manager (APAC) January 2007 - May 2009 (2 years 5 months)

Business development role across APAC.

Cisco Systems

Business Development Manager (SE Asia & India) January 2004 - December 2006 (3 years)

Business Development role covering Malaysia, Indonesia, Singapore & India.

Nortel Networks

Solutions Marketing Manager (APAC) January 1995 - December 2003 (9 years)

Singapore, Sydney and Kuala Lumpur

Solutions Marketing role based in Singapore, Sydney and Kuala Lumpur.

Education

Nottingham University Business School MBA, Financial with Merit · (2000 - 2007)

London South Bank University

BEng (Hons), Electrical and Electronics Engineering · (1990 - 1993)